questions = [
    {
        "question": "Which structure has 2 helices?",
        "options": ["DNA", "RNA", "cDNA"],
        "correct_answer": "DNA",
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main ingredient of DNA in the context of chemical compounds?",
        "options": ["Carbon", "Oxygen", "Phosphor"],
        "correct_answer": "Phosphor",
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the fastest source of energy?",
        "options": ["Protein", "Carbohydrates", "Lipids"],
        "correct_answer": "Carbohydrates",
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the full form of RNA?",
        "options": ["Ribonucleic Acid", "Deoxyribonucleic Acid", "Recombinant Nucleic Acid"],
        "correct_answer": "Ribonucleic Acid",
    },
    {
        "question": "Which genetic disorder is characterized by the absence of an X chromosome?",
        "options": ["Hemophilia", "Turner Syndrome", "Down Syndrome"],
        "correct_answer": "Turner Syndrome",
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the process of copying DNA information into RNA called?",
        "options": ["Translation", "Transcription", "Replication"],
        "correct_answer": "Transcription",
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organelle is responsible for the production of proteins in a cell?",
        "options": ["Mitochondria", "Endoplasmic Reticulum", "Ribosome"],
        "correct_answer": "Ribosome",
    },
     {
        "question": "Which DNA base pairs with adenine?",
        "options": ["Thymine", "Cytosine", "Guanine"],
        "correct_answer": "Thymine",
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for a segment of DNA that codes for a specific trait?",
        "options": ["Intron", "Exon", "Gene"],
        "correct_answer": "Gene",
    },
    {
        "question": "In humans, how many chromosomes are present in a normal somatic cell?",
        "options": ["46", "23", "32"],
        "correct_answer": "46",
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the process by which genetic material is exchanged between homologous chromosomes?",
        "options": ["Mitosis", "Meiosis", "Crossing Over"],
        "correct_answer": "Crossing Over",
    },
    {
        "question": "Which scientist is known for proposing the double helix structure of DNA?",
        "options": ["Gregor Mendel", "James Watson", "Francis Crick"],
        "correct_answer": "Francis Crick",
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for a change in the sequence of DNA bases?",
        "options": ["Mutation", "Transcription", "Replication"],
        "correct_answer": "Mutation",
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of RNA carries amino acids to the ribosome during protein synthesis?",
        "options": ["mRNA", "tRNA", "rRNA"],
        "correct_answer": "tRNA",
    },
]